{
    "id": "d7b18822483242788940b526ab3d202b",
    "title": "Common idiomatic expressions",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "2b936b8917914c7591c7eb63b97ef3d3",
            "title": "Common Idiomatic Expressions In English",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "‘OK everybody, lunch break is over. Now get back to the …………………...’",
                    "description": "To be back to the grind is to get back to work.",
                    "answers": [
                        "hearth",
                        "mill",
                        "grind"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘Did you get that job?’ ‘No mate, I ………………………… it.’",
                    "description": "I blew it = I missed my opportunity",
                    "answers": [
                        "cracked",
                        "blew",
                        "burst"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Her dreams of becoming a famous actor ended up just being a ……………………….. in the sky.",
                    "description": "Pie in the Sky = an unrealistic dream",
                    "answers": [
                        "speck",
                        "pie",
                        "star"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It was a ……………………. plan, so nobody was surprised when it failed.",
                    "description": "If something is half-baked, it hasn't been properly thought out or planned.",
                    "answers": [
                        "raw",
                        "half-baked",
                        "half-ripe"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………….. in there. Things should get better soon.",
                    "description": "This is an expression used to encourage people who are in a difficult situation. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Hang",
                        "Slide",
                        "Stand"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Writers of his caliber are hard to ………………………… by.",
                    "description": "If something is hard to come by, it is difficult to find.",
                    "answers": [
                        "get",
                        "come",
                        "meet"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She was hot under the ……………………… when she heard that they had lost that contract.",
                    "description": "If you are hot under the collar, you are angry or annoyed about something.",
                    "answers": [
                        "head",
                        "coat",
                        "sleeves",
                        "collar"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "I’m ……………………… and tired of eating the same thing for dinner every day.",
                    "description": "When you are sick and tired of something, you no longer find it interesting or exciting.",
                    "answers": [
                        "ill",
                        "sick",
                        "angry"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Your radio is starting to get on my ………………………. You had better it turn it down.",
                    "description": "To get on somebody’s nerves is to annoy them.",
                    "answers": [
                        "spine",
                        "nerves",
                        "spirits"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It is a small job but I am going to accept it. At least, I’ll have my ……………………. in the door.",
                    "description": "To get your foot in the door is to accept even a small job hoping that you would be able to get a promotion before long.",
                    "answers": [
                        "foot",
                        "leg",
                        "ankle"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You don’t have to pay for my drinks. Let’s go ………………………..",
                    "description": "To go Dutch is to pay your own share.",
                    "answers": [
                        "French",
                        "Spanish",
                        "Dutch"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He tends to sell himself …………………… and that is his main fault.",
                    "description": "To sell somebody short is to describe them as less impressive than they really are.",
                    "answers": [
                        "short",
                        "low",
                        "less"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}